# CHAITALI DIKHOLKAR

**Data Analyst** 

Infront of shri ram towers, dabki road,, Akola, 444002, India dikholkarc@gmail.com 9404702601

# **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Experienced Data Analyst with 6+ months in identifying data inefficiencies and communicating project needs, proficient in SQL, Access, and Excel. Successfully generated audit reports that improved compliance by 15%. Capable of synthesizing quantitative information and collaborating effectively with colleagues and clients. Demonstrated success in generating summary documents for senior management to support monthly and quarterly audit and compliance reporting.

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

# Faculty Lecturer, Shankarlal Khendelwal college, Akola

08/2022 - Present

- Spearheaded curriculum enhancements for senior college courses, resulting in a 25% boost in student satisfaction scores and a 20% improvement in graduation rates over a two-year period
- Participated in courses of computer science department, delivered knowledge on, subjects like Artificial Intelligence
  and machine learning, computer system organization, cyber security, also cultivated young learners with knowledge
  and ethics by building confidence level up to 20%
- Proactively Consolidated resources for after college activities, Increased student satisfaction scores Boosted by 15%

# Lecturer, RLT college, Akola

08/2023 - Present

- Directed and mentored 200+ students at senior college, incorporating innovative teaching methods that increased student engagement by 30% and improved overall course performance by 15% over year
- Highly skilled computer science professional, delivered knowledge on subjects like business intelligence(BI), SQL, Java, mobile computing, operating system and algorithms
- Increased student satisfaction scores by 25%

# **EDUCATION**

# MSc (Computer Science), Shri Shivaji College of Arts, Commerce, and Science, Akola

07/2017 - 06/2019

- Achieved a CGPA of 6.66.
- Participated in workshops covering IOT, Android app development, Ethical Hacking, and Computer Fundamentals.

## Academic project:

## Leftover Food Helpline — Android-based Online Mobile Application

• **Description:** Developed an outstanding online mobile application using Android Studio, Java, XML, and HTML. Facilitated food donation registration for certified NGOs.

## Responsibilities:

- Gathered and analyzed project requirements.
- Designed user forms, backend, and frontend interfaces.
- Managed and maintained backend databases and admin dashboards.

Skills: HTML, XML, Java, And Java Script

Technology: Android Studio, SQL Server

**Results**: Successfully developed an application that reduced food waste by 15% and alleviated starvation by up to 10% through NGO collaboration.

# BCA, Shankarlal Khandelwal College, Akola

07/2014 - 06/2017

- Achieved a percentage of 67.10%.
- Participated in a C programming competition and achieved a score of 75%, ranking 25th out of 300 candidates.

## academic project:

## Paperless Wedding Hall System-Desktop based application

- Description: Developed a desktop-based application using Visual Basic and Excel databases.
- Responsibilities: Gathered and Invented project requirements. Designed user forms and interfaces. Controlled and maintained the backend databases.

SKILLS  R Programming(tidyverse, ggplot,dplyr)	SQL(MySql server, Workbench)
Python(NumPy, Pandas)	Tableau, PowerBI
Excel / Google sheets	Database Management Systems (MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQL Server, MongoDB, Cassandra)
ETL Tools (Talend, Informatica)	Data Warehousing Solutions (Amazon Redshift, Google Big-Query)
Cloud Services (AWS, Azure, Google Cloud Platform)	Data Cleaning and Preprocessing Libraries (Pandas, tidyverse)
Statistics	Data Visualization
Dashboarding	Communication
Critical Thinking and Problem Solving	Analytical Thinking
Story Telling	Attention to Detail

#### LINKS

Linkedin

GitHub

Kaggle

# **CERTIFIED COURSES**

Google Data Analytics Certificate, Coursera

08/2022 - 07/2024

**SQL** for Data Science, Great Learning Academy

08/2021 - 08/2021

Python for Data Science, Great Learning Academy

# **EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

# National science day, RLT college, Akola

02/2024 - 02/2024

- Organized and hosted a national science day event, showcasing a poster competition.
- Worked collaboratively with a team of 5 colleagues.
- Took the lead in organizing competition logistics and ensuring adherence to timelines.

# Volunteering, Akola

08/2023 - 08/2023

- Engaged in community service initiatives to promote empathy and create positive change at Berar Education Society.
- Contributed to the education decision-making committee, influencing strategic decisions to enhance educational outcomes.

# Student Government, RLT college, Akola

09/2023 - 09/2023

 Assumed leadership responsibilities and played a key role in college decision-making processes for student internships at Microspectra.

# **PROJECTS**

# **Analysis of Cyclistic Bike Share Users**

06/2024

Goal: To determine the differences between casual users and members.

#### **Description:**

- Evaluated a dataset from Cyclistic Bike Share Company covering 2019-2020.
- Data Investigated ride id, rideable type, started at, ended at, start station name, start station id, member casual, and other relevant information.
- Tasks Conducted loading, cleaning, and preprocessing data; performing exploratory data analysis (EDA); and analyzing the correlation between user type and ride duration.
- Implemented correlation statistical analysis using R packages ggplot, ggplot2, and libraries tidyverse, tidyr, and lubridate

**Skills**: Data cleaning, ETL process, data analysis, correlation matrices, hypothesis testing, data visualization, correlation analysis, dashboard designing. Technology: R, tidyverse, tidyr, ggplot, ggplot2, ggvis, lubridate.

Results: Discovered that weekday ride duration and user type highly correlate with gross earnings. Identified casual users as long riders (89,820 seconds) and members as short riders (89,880 seconds). Example: Created a successful training program for new Junior Administrative Assistants to build their skills with Google Workspace and MS Office.

# Analysis of Cyclistic Bike Share Users and Bike Type Preferences 2024

06/2024

**Goal**: To determine the differences between casual users and members, and to analyze bike type preferences of both user groups.

## **Description:**

- Examined a dataset from Cyclistic Bike Share Company for January to June 2024.
- Data Encompassed ride id, rideable type, started at, ended at, star station name, start station id, member casual, and other relevant information.
- Tasks Scrutinized loading, cleaning, and preprocessing data; performing exploratory data analysis (EDA); and analyzing the correlation between user type and ride duration.
- Directed correlation statistical analysis using R packages ggplot, ggplot2, and libraries tidyverse, tidyr, and lubridate.

**Skills**: Data cleaning, ETL process, data analysis, correlation matrices, hypothesis testing, data visualization, correlation analysis, dashboard designing, storytelling, R-markdown. Technology: R, tidyverse, tidyr, ggplot, ggplot2, ggvis, lubridate.

## Results:

- Appraise user behavior using R functions, revealing a high correlation between user type and ride duration on weekdays with gross earnings.
- Diagnosed casual users as having maximum ride times of 89,820 seconds.
- Locate that both user types showed a high preference for classic bike types on all days.